DC Oral History Collaborative Collection 180
People's Archive, MLK Library
- Series 12: The Brookland Literary And Hunting Club (BLAHC): It's Not What You Think!, 2018
  - Sub-Series 1: Interviews, 2018
    - Wilhelmina Banks interview, 2018-05-03
      Wilhelmina Banks was born in Richmond, Virginia on June 9, 1928. She recalls growing up in a loving home with close relationships with her parents and aunt. She recalled no personal negative consequences of segregated life. Her parents protected her from strife and conflict, and she had a consistent group of friends around her. She went on to college at Howard University, where she met her future husband, Quentin Banks (now deceased, former member of BLAHC). They had 4 children including Jock Banks (current member of BLAHC). She pursued graduate education in speech and language pathology and was sent to Columbia University because there were no segregated colleges in the south for her to do so. She had a long career for Prince George's County School System as a Speech Language Pathologist. She recalled her experiences playing poker with her husband and other couples and spoke about his love for BLAHC. He loved the poker, but mostly loved the conversations about current events.
      In this oral history Wilhelmina Banks reflects on raising her family and her work as a speech therapist in the Prince George's County, Maryland schools, where she worked for 52 years. She sees the literary and hunting club as being important as a place for the men to engage in intellectual exchanges just as much it is a place for them to play poker. A poker player herself, Wilhelmina sees the game as valuable for its social aspects. She speaks about her decision to go to Howard University, where dorm life is a key place for her to make friends. She then talks getting married a year after meeting her husband then spending the rest of her life with him. The oral history also contains her reflections on the benefits of speech therapy and laments budget cuts that have resulted in schools replacing human speech therapists with computers. She spoke about her family's beach house at Highland Beach, a historically Black beach town near Annapolis, MD which was frequented by Frederick Douglass.
    - Walter K. Robinson interview, 2018-04-18
      Walter K. Robinson, Sr. was born in Baltimore, Maryland in 1920, the second son of Dr. John C. Robinson and Mrs. Clara Denning Robinson. In 1941, while attending Howard University in Washington, D.C., he volunteered for the Army Air Corps. He became one of the Tuskegee Airmen. After an injury, recuperation, and completion of training, WWII ended and his service and experiences have been well documented recently. His experiences as a Tuskegee Airman have shaped his life and he carries the work ethic and perseverance he learned there into his entire life. He married his high school sweetheart, Edmonia Bailey. In 1945 he received an honorable discharge and returned to Civilian life. He and his wife moved to D.C. in 1959. He worked for the U.S. Postal Service for 35 years. He rose through the ranks as Clerk, Station Manager, and the second Black Manager of Delivery and Collection for D.C. He and his wife had one son, Walter K. Robinson Jr. Mrs. Robinson died in 2000, after 59 years of marriage. Mr. Robinson still lives in D.C. and is a very active member of the East Coast Chapter of the Tuskegee Airmen. They won a Congressional Gold Medal as a group in March 2007. In the 1970s, he and his peers came to realize how important their legacy was and they formed the East Coast Chapter.
      Walter K. Robinson, Sr., talks about his life going up in Baltimore, Maryland; time in the Tuskegee Airman; marrying his high school sweetheart; and his career in the post office in Washington, D.C. During the dialogue he reflects on segregation and desegregation. For decades, the Brookland Literary and Hunting Club has been a place that he goes for relaxation and companionship.
    - Frank Sanders interview, 2018-05-10
      Frank Sander is a commissioner for the D.C. Real Property Tax Appeals Commission. A long-time resident of Washington, D.C., Sanders was born and raised in Chicago. He briefly worked as a teacher before going to business school and building a career in real estate. A proud father of two, now grown, children, he continues to live in Washington, D.C. with his wife of over 30 years.
      In the interview Frank Sanders talks about his love for poker and how sometimes he can play for 15 hours in one day. This, and his commitment to understanding the history of the African American community in Washington D.C., lead him to join the Brookland Literary and Hunting Club. Sanders reflects on growing up in Chicago, Illinois, a city he found to be segregated in a manner so harsh that it was impossible to enter certain neighborhoods, and how he found Washington, D.C. to be a more cosmopolitan place to live. After receiving a degree in teaching, he spent a few years teaching third grade before going back to school to learn finance and business. He began a career in real estate, where he remained until business began to dry-up in the wake of the 2008 financial crisis at which point he joined the D.C. Real Property Tax Appeals Commission. Poker, and the Brookland Literary and Hunting Club, continue to be a source of relaxation and community for him.
  - Sub-Series 2: Indexes, 2018
    - James Butts interview index, 2018
    - Jock Banks interview index, 2018
    - Thomas Taylor index, 2018
    - Wilhelmina Banks interview index, 2018
    - Walter K. Robinson interview index, 2018
    - Frank Sanders interview index, 2018
  - Sub-Series 3: transcripts, 2018
    - James Butts interview transcript, 2018
    - Jock Banks interview transcript, 2018
    - Thomas Taylor transcript, 2018
    - Wilhelmina Banks interview transcript, 2018
    - Walter K. Robinson interview transcript, 2018
    - Frank Sanders interview transcript, 2018